Yes Sonam is equal to gold and gold
is also equal to gold what does it mean that
if we sleep and get a sweet sleep then
we have one and a half section that yes
we have woken up and media
is equal to that gold similarly if we have gold in our house then
we will sleep peacefully and it is equal to that being
oh what do you want to say so
if we talk about India, it is
found in everyone's house gold is
such a popular form of investment
or there is an emotional attachment too
people buy it at every option with open heart
and definitely keep some in the house
in their time our grandmothers used to
tell me that if gold is kept at home if any
trouble comes or any decision is to be taken then we will take it out there there are a lot of
disadvantages in keeping it in Gurgaon, I have illuminated it, then we have to
take designer meeting on side that
if we keep it then 15 to 20 percent of your money
goes waste if you
invest it properly then the second thing that happens is that it was
kept in storage
but if you keep it then it is accurate that it does not get damaged  If it is
kept in the bank locker, there is a weakness problem, then in MP and if there is no
quality of gold, how many carats of
gold, how much is it, how much is it, how many amperes is it, we went to the jeweler and bought it, how much is it, only that can be
said, so today I will talk to you about what other
ways are there in which you
can keep this investment with you, my name is Cooling and Chiku
and I bring such videos for you in
which I try to answer some of your
questions
related to personal pension, so
if you have not subscribed to our channel yet, then
please subscribe to our channel
and join us, there are
five ways to invest in gold, which are
physical
gold, digital gold, gold ETF and
gold mutual fund and then which are all these
projects involved, some have some advantages, some have some
disadvantages and where you can use it,
we will talk about that, so first is
physical gold, physical gold and it is taken as a guest,
that is bullion,
yours,
so here that problem is  There is no
impurity of 124 carat gold in
Lucknow, this means if we are buying the tree then the
floor is not there, the protein is
complete, now when we are taking investment then we are
not even giving
meeting charges which goes up to 15 to 20 rupees,
but whenever it is not there then it is being
taken in the manner of pure investment, but the
problem here is the problem of next storage, the
problem is that if it rains then
where will we store it, if we keep it in the bike, if we keep it
at home then the juice will remain forever,
hence the second option will come, so digital
gold is digital gold, that is the digital
format of which you can adopt, you can buy it from any place
like this which is available on every digital platform nowadays,
like your Paytm, it is on Google,
now it is on Zara, you can buy it from Stock Holding Corporation,
you can buy gold from all these places,
minimum investment at District Coordinator is ₹1, maximum
50,000, if you invest more than fifty thousand
then return is required, so
what happens to this  From where we are
buying digital, what do we do, we do
sauce from the front, then we do an episode of shell,
first two
Shravan TCP, Embassy Indian Companies,
Paint Company, so there is this joint venture, so
from there we
fold the thing and fold it from the award,
so this is 3 meters from where this course is done,
where it lies in the world of hard,
now you can buy and sell it anytime, you can also take it and
sell it, it can
also be liquid, so liquid is also a
problem, if you want to share it, then it becomes
liquid, then for
how long can you keep it, 5 years, you
can see here, you have the option
or you can take delivery of it and
you
should get it made, you can use any MS Word office
and you can check the charges,
you can take delivery of it with different types
or it can be negligible,
where you take delivery of it and that it
is negligible in this answer building, but if you are taking it, then
you can check it automatically in it
We will talk
about Gold ETF. First of all, we understood what
it is. It is an exchange
traded fund. Meaning, if you want to invest in any asset, then
you need to open a demat account for percentage profit.
Suppose you want to invest in Parliament, then
you invest through the midcap of Sensex.
Whatever you want in front at this stage, then all the securities in Parliament are
changed on the media. If you
invest in Nifty ETF, in
that also, all the securities in Nifty will
purchase your idea.
This happens in debt securities also.
Similarly, there is also Gold ETF,
it is invested in the details. So, in the solution,
investment is also made in gold through exchange. Investment is made in proper gold and in
gold mining and finally in the company.
In this,
activities are kept from zero to ten percent.
To maintain liquidity, the
next option is Gold Mutual Fund. So,
basically, you can also invest offline. There is
no need for its demand.
And if you are going in one direction in mutual funds, then
a fund of funds.  It means that the Gold Mutual Fund is
investing in Gold ETF,
so what is happening in it, if you
found it foolish, then the expense ratio of Gold Fund is one to one,
you have found the
problem, yes now 10 grams of fennel from one pan, the
institute will also do optional circulation,
your greed will increase and a lot, which became
very popular last year, many
issues of Sovereign Gold Bonds were
launched every month, people invested a lot of money in it,
12.5 from one side and it is very
secure and measurement is guaranteed,
type Prasanna National Interest is also being given on it,
fixed Jodi is double, definition
interest is given and how do you take it from the front,
what is the difference between physical gold, digital gold, Gold ETFS going in for empowering don, so first we will talk about the
cost, what is the cost, when we
talk about the toss, first IGST is difficult for us,
and if we are opening digital, then
3% GST has to be paid on both the legs,
horse mutual funds in Gold ETF  And there's
no one in the universe to talk about this storage and translation
for delivery case. So the first
possible goal is the sun. There's nothing else. If we
talk about it, we can enter a role in a bank account
for someone. If we
need sun, we've
got cost management. Goli, date,
good
loot medical stores, and let's talk about
Dimple. Putting a difficult chilli in it,
it might cost a small sun,
which is two to three percent.
Next time, we need a pen. Because
in the first two, there's nothing like this. Even if
we're taking a physical account, crops do
n't mean anything. And in a digital solution, there's no
goli. Delhi-110 085. If you're taking a white demand
account, you might incur a 4% to 1%
expense ratio. The
expense ratio of choice is half a percent.
Talking about gold ETFs and mutual funds,
your mutual fund expense ratio is half a percent to one and a half percent.
Appointment today is also called
plus because I told you this fund.  If it
is an off fund then the cost of Gold ETF will be the
same. So, how half to one percent of gold was being used will be the same. So
overall you
can assume that it will cost one and a half to two percent
every year. There are no expense ratios in the Supreme Court. There is no
course,
no additional exit. We will talk about those. I
mean if you
want to withdraw your money then how much can it cost us.
Physical gold cannot be ignored. You
can keep half of it close to your body. There is
no ad in digital gold also. If we talk about GPS, you
can withdraw your money by reading some exams at any time. In mutual funds, there is
239 in it,
like in 1995, 1968, if
you are investing before a year, and
if we talk about one want because it
is dutiable, this third is double, then there is
no objection in them. There will be a mix up on brokerage,
how much is charged in the past, DP is charged at four places
if we keep it and
how much is the securities transaction tax, we will
talk about that first. There is nothing in
physical gold in digital gold.  There is
no job. If we talk about Gold ETF, it can be done
with a towel. If we
believe in political conspiracy also, then it may take some
defense and time. We charge annual maintenance
charges. And if there are
two types of trees in the heat and
all are through Twitter account, then
you will not see any progress. I do not have a separate pass.
Otherwise, if you go to the black market point, then there is a
little loss on your investment
because there is procreation waste in it.
Sovereign Gautam also does
not have police. So let's talk about other factors,
like we just talked about what is the
cost, what is the expense ratio, what is the
exit load, let's
talk about everything else, like liquidity,
if we talk about liquidity, then also
in the race, when can you go on holidays, go to the jeweler and
send it and bring your money home.
Liquid is shown in the digital form that you can
buy anytime. Let's talk about June Gold Digger
because it is not popular in India, so
I had become Megha. There is moderate liquidity
that you get it again and again in the market.  You
can see it in the secondary market, it
sells well, it's not difficult at all.
This isn't a chilli idli dosa. The second is your
food misal pav inch. There's no problem with liquidity here
because you're
buying intermediate Surya chilli and points, so
you can have some security, then we'll
talk about four things. You could get it on the
secondary market. Firstly, it takes
time for this to be done. You apply for deposits in the village.
When the Supreme Court
saw that a baby was born every month, you open a 45-day account.
You can subscribe.
And if you want to sell in the middle,
it's on the plunderers. The rate of the pavs will be going on in
Kolkata. You can also sell on that. But
here too, the motive is liquidity.
Another factor on which we will compare gold
options is that you can add gold options to physical gold.
No, you can't do that alone. You
can buy them systematically, but you
can't invest in any asset class or struggle.
As mentioned, there are SIT options in the application. You can invest in cycles. There is
also no acidity test for acidity. Currently, there
is no mutual fund option.
You will get the option of SIP in sovereign bond
also, there is no add by option in sovereign bond, it will be taken
one time, yes whenever you take it and if we
talk about minimum investment in this way, if you are going to take
arm hole then you will open
minimum physical gold in grams and if you
open diesel then you can give digit of ₹1 and
in Gold ETF, minimum is being asked and
Gold Mutual Fund minimum is ₹5, there is a
judgment in Supreme Court also that minimum
investment is of one gram, if we
talk about delivery then delivery is
possible in physical gold, it is of ready Vimal
and in digital solution also minimum is being done
from Brahma Nagar Agra, you
can take delivery, in Gold ETF
if you open minimum then delivery
option is given, there is
no delivery option in mutual fund and Supreme
Court does not want with delivery option, so
these were some options in which we talked about
how you can buy horses, there
is physical gold, digital gold, Gold
ETF and mutual fund for removal point,
so everything is on the side and  If there is some loss then
Amazon may trouble you, then on the basis of this you
can decide that if you
want to buy then you can go through sperm
and you can also do this, you can keep some
digital gold,
put some in warm water and
keep some physical gold also because until that gets
traction then those clicks do
not come, you have invested a
little, keep some physical gold
in deposit scheme, then the donkeys, let us
talk about where you can buy
physical gold, you can go and buy it from a jeweler,
Bismil, we
talked about the application, you can buy Paytm on my Google phone from
here,
if you open a demat account anywhere, you
can like its gold,
you can
buy it directly by going to the website of 68 management companies, you can
buy it through another distributor, if there is Swapna Dosh, where your
mind is fine, you can change it here
and the favorable point, then on the basis of this you
can decide, from where and how to take it and the
mixture dance as I have done  I told you
cannot mix and match, see this, in this
way the government matches and
my only hope is that your
life should be golden like someone's, your financial
times should be golden like a horse and you should get good
education and if you have any question about Vikas
Bhole Management and want to give some suggestion, if
someone wants to donate then please do so,
if you liked the video after using it then
please do share it, do like it, it gives you
motivation to
make more videos, you will get it quickly
in this video, bye-bye take care and become a fast member